<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GDG Akure</title>
    <description>Sharing Technology. For Designers, Developers and Serious Tech Enthusiasts.</description>
    <link>http://akure.gdg.ng/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://akure.gdg.ng/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Things to expect at google i/o 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Google&#39;s I/O 2015 conference starts Thursday with a monster 2.5-hour keynote. Android M, the next major version of Google&#39;s mobile operating system, is likely to lead the way. You can expect Google to run through its usual showcase of Android&#39;s latest and greatest features on stage, and it&#39;s likely the company will shine a similar spotlight on Android Wear and Android Auto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Google has also been keeping busy with Chrome OS, virtual reality, and its Project Fi cellular service. It&#39;s a thrilling time to be following the company, and you&#39;ll want to keep it locked on The Verge when Sundar Pichai takes the stage Thursday at 12:30PM ET . We&#39;ll be live from Moscone West bringing you all the news as it happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android M: Google&#39;s own I/O schedule confirmed that we&#39;ll be seeing a new version of Android at the keynote. After giving Android a huge visual overhaul with Lollipop, we expect the next iteration to focus on refining Material Design further, squashing bugs, and improving performance. More powerful voice controls are likely on the agenda, and knowing Google, the company will probably also boast about longer-than-ever battery life. If the company follows last year&#39;s pattern, we&#39;ll have to wait a few months before finding out what the &quot;M&quot; stands for. But on the plus side, it&#39;s likely you&#39;ll be able to install a preview build of Android for Nexus 6 and Nexus 6 very soon after the keynote wraps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More privacy controls: Earlier this month, Bloomberg reported that Google is planning to give Android users greater control over apps and exactly what data they&#39;re able to access (location, contacts, photos, et cetera). Android already presents a list of requested permissions whenever you download an app from Google Play, but this approach will reportedly be adjusted to let users &quot;pick and choose what an app can access.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fingerprints: Last week, BuzzFeed reported that Android M will introduce full-fledged support for fingerprint authentication, letting users log into apps like Gmail and Google Drive with the press of a thumb. The Galaxy S6 proved that fingerprint scanners on Android phones don&#39;t have to suck, and soon they&#39;ll be even better. Expect Google to embrace this and move closer to offering its own take on Apple&#39;s Touch ID; obviously manufacturers will need to include the hardware on their phones and tablets, but the deep-level support will make that decision far easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android Wear: It was just over one year ago when Google unveiled a version of Android designed for your wrist. Since then, the company has been working rapidly to bring new features and improvements to Android Wear. The roster of devices running Google&#39;s wearables OS has steadily grown in the last year, though we&#39;re still waiting for the second iteration of Motorola&#39;s Moto 360. The timing is almost right, but an I/O debut is by no means guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android Auto: Similarly, Google will likely have plenty to say about its mission of putting Android into cars. Automaker partnerships are critical to that effort, so Google could have some news to share there. Over the last year, we&#39;ve also seen rumors that Google has loftier ambitions that go far beyond the tacked-on experience offered by Android Auto (and Apple&#39;s CarPlay) today. But I/O will likely be more about building more momentum for the current product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android Pay: Isis (Softcard) is dead, and no one is benefitting from that more than Google. The company has formed a deep partnership with Verizon, AT&amp;T, and T-Mobile — something that was unthinkable just a few years ago — to make Google Wallet the new standard for mobile payments on Android devices. We expect to hear more about Google&#39;s grand vision for taking on the wallet (and Apple Pay) at I/O. Whether the Google Wallet brand will stick around is unclear, as Google may opt for a simpler, familiar name in Android Pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Photos : Google is breaking out one of Google+&#39;s best features into its own product. We expect Google Photos to carry forward some of the existing service&#39;s best ideas (automatic GIFs and &quot;Auto Awesome&quot; photo enhancements) while trying to appeal to a broader market of consumers. Shedding the Google+ connection is one great way to accomplish that. How much will it cost? Right now Google offers unlimited storage of regular-sized images for free, and it&#39;s one of our favorite photo backup options as a result. The stand-alone version just might top our list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Fi: Google is now a mobile phone carrier — if you happen to own a Nexus 6. With Project Fi invites slowly trickling out , I/O presents the company with another good opportunity to demonstrate the pay-for-what-you-use phone service that seamlessly hops between Wi-Fi and two major US networks (Sprint and T-Mobile).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet of Things: With mobile devices, wearables, and automobiles already checked off, Google will reportedly next turn its attention to household appliances . The company is said to be planning a big entry into the Internet of Things, and at I/O we&#39;re expecting to hear more about the software Google has created to control all of these various low-power gadgets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cardboard: Is virtual reality becoming more than a fun experiment for Google? Last month&#39;s announcement of the Works with Cardboard program shows that Mountain View is looking to the future with its answer to the Oculus Rift and Samsung&#39;s own VR project. But experience is key, and so far Google hasn&#39;t really produced any compelling reasons for strapping a smartphone onto your face. I/O should provide some clues as to how serious Google is about virtual reality — or whether it&#39;ll forever remain a side pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Cast: The $35 Chromecast is one of the best devices that Google has ever made, and it&#39;s led developers to quickly embrace the company&#39;s AirPlay rival. With video pretty well covered, Google has recently put a bigger emphasis on music with the introduction of Google Cast for Audio. The I/O stage seems a natural place to reveal new speakers that support Google&#39;s tech. And a Chromecast 2 seems inevitable; the only question is when.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrome: It&#39;s no secret that Android and Chrome OS are moving toward one another. And while they&#39;re likely to remain separate for the foreseeable future, Google has every interest in making its operating systems play nice together. You can bet the company will demonstrate the benefits of this cohesive strategy that blends the web and mobile. I/O could also produce some surprise Chromebook announcements ahead of back-to-school season.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://akure.gdg.ng/blog/things-to-expect-at-google-io-2015</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://akure.gdg.ng/blog/things-to-expect-at-google-io-2015</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GDG AKure in Review[2014]</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2014, the tech community in Nigeria as a whole grew in leaps and bounds and the GDGAkure is glad to be a part of that growth. We come bringing news and innovation from the bigger tech community and we want to share what we have learned and hope that that would help us grow together as a community. 
Since we started, we have had a tonne of events, some with major successes. Now it is time to bring everyone to be a full member of the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we are dealing with a community of over 100 people who have different devices and communication preferences, we believe that communicating via a mailing list would be most effective. We have seen it work in other GDGs across Nigeria, Africa and the World at large and we believe it to work for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 
The URL for our mailing list is  &lt;a href=&quot;&gt;bitly.com/gdgakuremailinglist&quot;&gt;bitly.com/gdgakuremailinglist&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
The URL for our blog is &lt;a href=&quot;gdgakure.blogspot.com&quot;&gt;gdgakure.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
On Google plus, &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/+GdgakureBlogspot&quot;&gt;https://plus.google.com/+GdgakureBlogspot&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Over the course of the year, we have had two events with over 600participants in total &lt;br&gt;
- Google FUTA &lt;br&gt;
- Google I/O Extended &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the end of the year, we still want to have 3 event, we would like to involve as many people as possible in the planning of our future events. In the course of the year, we had 6 events and one large event and a DevFest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; We welcome any suggestion no matter how wild, afterall, we would be solving for our own X pretty soon. 
We welcome feedback, concerns, critisism, anything that could help us grow, we are always ready to listen.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	 DISCLAIMER: &lt;br&gt;
If you did not get the solveforx joke, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.solveforx.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.solveforx.com/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
I don&#39;t know why Google plus Decided to Add blogspot to our URI &lt;br&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://akure.gdg.ng/blog/GDG-Akure-in-review-2014</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://akure.gdg.ng/blog/GDG-Akure-in-review-2014</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Polymer 101: An Introduction to Material Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt; For everybody that watched the Google I/O keynote you&#39;d know about the new material design that google is implementing in the web, and trying to change the way we have web experiences, if maybe you didnt have the opportunity to watch the Google I/O key note maybe you should just head over to Google Design and have a feel of how it actually is... this development was actually rolled out to be the main big thing for the upcoming android L but then Google decided to extend it to the web so the released a library called POLYMER check it out the website at &lt;a href=&quot;http://polymer-project.org/&quot;&gt;The Polymer website&lt;/a&gt; kinda of like jQuery, Bootstrap to help with incorporating it in our webpages... it should be noted that apparently the design ability has being extended to Angular.JS too for yall that already have an hang of Angular.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So leaving all the great news behind this is a kind of tutorial on setting up the polymer designer tool locally on your system, since for some of us maybe the steps on the polymer website is kind of overwhelming i know it was for me. if you&#39;ve headed over to the polymer website to get a feel of it you&#39;d notice that there is a designer tool on the website to help generate the polymer code for us... maybe you dont have the intermittent internet connection to do fiddle around with it this is the guide to help you set it up locally so you can have all the time in the whole world to fiddle and learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;So items we&#39;ll need or you probably have to download first:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        you have to install a git client (http://git-scm.com/downloads) you&#39;ll need it cause you would be fetching files from github add git into your environment variables if you try typing &lt;em&gt;&quot;git&quot;&lt;/em&gt; on your cmd prompt and you get path is not defined, add PATH =&quot;C:\Program Files (x86)\Git\bin;&quot;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Node.Js, head over to http://nodejs.org/download it just a 5mb installer or so also youll need to add node to your environment variables PATH= &quot;C:\Users\yourusername\AppData\Roaming\npm;&quot;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
       Next you need Bower on nodeJs after installing it open the command line and run &lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;npm bower install&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, bower helps you pull other components the developer used that the project requires to work 
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
       polymer would not run without an HTTP server running, so inside your nodeJS run &lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;npm install serve&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt; it will help you install a mini  http server that can handle polymer all you have to do is cd into your project and run &lt;em&gt;&quot;serve&quot;&lt;/em&gt; on your command line and it automatically serves your directory on &lt;em&gt;&quot;http://localhost:3000&quot;&lt;/em&gt; 
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        then head over to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Polymer/designer&quot;&gt;github polmer designer page&lt;/a&gt; either clone the project or download the zip folder to your PC
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;follow the steps in the README file&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
         cd into your project directory, run &lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;bower install&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, if youve done everything correctly you will see npm download quite some files. when it completes start up your serve with &quot;serve&quot; and load &lt;em&gt;&quot;http://localhost:3000&quot;&lt;/em&gt; viola there you have it the designer locally.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6&gt; Now to gain an understanding of Polymer a little Hello World example:&lt;/h6&gt;

&amp;nbsp

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 2&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Test&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 3&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;charset=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 4&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;http-equiv=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;X-UA-Compatible&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;content=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;IE-edge,chrome=1&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 5&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;name=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;content=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 6&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 7&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- you can get the polymer.js and platform.js by running bower install polymer on node.js --&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 8&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;script &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;src=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;bower_components/platform/platform.js&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 9&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- one of the new concept rolled off polymer is the ability to import into an html just like the @import in css --&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;link&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;rel=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;import&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;bower_components/polymer/polymer.html&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;          
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- we start my creating a polymer element thats named, attr noscript is added to let the browser no not to expect any script --&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;15&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;polymer-element&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;name=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;test&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;noscript&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- we then create a template to encase our content, this is all based on the shadow DOM concept, even I am just trying to grasp the whole idea --&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;18&lt;/span&gt;             &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;template&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;19&lt;/span&gt;               &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;style&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;                 &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;21&lt;/span&gt;                 &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#ccf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;                     &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;23&lt;/span&gt;               &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/style&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;24&lt;/span&gt;                 &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Hello Eyo!&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;25&lt;/span&gt;             &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/template&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;26&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/polymer-element&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;27&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- now to call what we wrote inside our polymer element template, we simply just use the name of our polymer element as a tag --&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;28&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!--- and it displays the info in the named element, so it should be noted that the styles applied inside the elemnt are encapusalted to test only  --&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;29&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;test&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/test&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;30&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- any other normal html tag placed anywhere inside the html document is exposed to the global style, for instance--&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;31&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;I am default&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;32&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;33&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;P.S. You need to have an HTTP server for any of this run, else it&#39;d seem like your getting it wrong&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://akure.gdg.ng/blog/Polymer-101-an-introduction-to-material-design</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://akure.gdg.ng/blog/Polymer-101-an-introduction-to-material-design</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>#GCDC Akure</title>
        <description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-0Nuw-S93p_g/UlJegwIZEXI/AAAAAAAADaY/lbtxCl95UFw/s640/Banner+(2).png&quot; style=&quot;align:center;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Challenge! It&#39;s time to show the world what you can do with the Google Cloud Platform.
Three Sessions, Three Languages, One Platform
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;PHP on App Engine (Recommended for theNigerian Website Developer)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Python on App Engine (Recommended for Beginners)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Java on App Engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Registration link is here &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/CK5XM0&quot;&gt;http://goo.gl/CK5XM0&lt;/a&gt; &amp;nbsp
Google + Event Page is here &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/oajk6g&quot;&gt;http://goo.gl/oajk6g&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Event Details&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Date: 12th October 2013&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Venue: Royal Birds Alagbaka, Akure, Nigeria&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Time: 10am to 2pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://akure.gdg.ng/blog/GCDC-Akure</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://akure.gdg.ng/blog/GCDC-Akure</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minutes after DevFest Akure</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;DevFest akure was tagged &quot;Reviving a Process&quot;. It was setup to be a training for developers on Google Technologies, disguised as a Hackathon.

66 People said Yes they would be coming on Google+, These individuals included students, developers and professionals from across Akure.
45 People Turned up for the Event, Not counting the Speakers and the Organizers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Program started at 10:30 with a short introduction to The program. This was taken by &lt;a href=&quot;http://plus.google.com/103244551260750496913&quot;&gt;+Tomiwa Ijaware&lt;/a&gt;, Next we had a Presentation on Software Development at 10, 000ft. This presentation tried to introduce the pieces that makes a working software. He emphasized the Use of OAuth, HTML5, CSS3, Google App Engine and Mobile Applications and Source Control, and promised that this would be taken in details over the cause of the meetup. He Then had a practical session where people documented the users they would be targeting for the development of their apps
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Next Session was on Source Control with Git, It was started by &lt;a href=&quot;http://plus.google.com/115354888144009772047&quot;&gt;+Samuel Okoroafor&lt;/a&gt;. Samuel explained what Source control was and showed the pull - change - commit - push cycle. He then started the practical session where he guided people in the Source Control Practical. There was brief difficulty with internet access, but the network finally came through. Due to an urgent Call, &lt;a href=&quot;http://plus.google.com/115354888144009772047&quot;&gt;+Samuel Okoroafor&lt;/a&gt; had to stop halfway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This session was continued by &lt;a href=&quot;http://plus.google.com/104110587868441041122&quot;&gt;+ADEKOLA ADEBAYO&lt;/a&gt; who continued the Source control Practical Session. This session came to a close and was immediately followed by a brief Session on Google Apps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://plus.google.com/113375950149684624825&quot;&gt;+iyanuoluwa bolarinwa&lt;/a&gt; Educated people on performing basic tasks with Google Drive and Gmail. After this, we had Lunch at 1:30pm, 
The Session Resuned at 2:00 with a Session on Google App Engine taken by &lt;a href=&quot;http://plus.google.com/104110587868441041122&quot;&gt;+ADEKOLA ADEBAYO&lt;/a&gt;. Kola First Explained AppEngine and then moved into the AppEngine Practical. The BackEnd of a Simple To Do List App was built. This session made use of the knowledge gotten from Source Control. The To Do service Built also was available for mobile devices via the Google Cloud Endpoints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately after this, &lt;a href=&quot;http://plus.google.com/110696408351640467234&quot;&gt;+Akinwande Adegbola&lt;/a&gt; went straight into creating the Android Client for the To Do Application. People were especially thrilled when they saw their work finally working on their Android Phones.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, &lt;a href=&quot;http://plus.google.com/115354888144009772047&quot;&gt;+Samuel Okoroafor&lt;/a&gt; gave the Vote of Thanks, and a lot of Pictures were taken about the event.
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://akure.gdg.ng/blog/minutes-after-devfest-akure</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://akure.gdg.ng/blog/minutes-after-devfest-akure</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Map Up Akure</title>
        <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://sites.google.com/site/mapyourworldcommunity/_/rsrc/1330465412277/config/customLogo.gif?revision=18&quot; style=&quot;align:center;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Map up Akure is a community driven event sponsored by Eco-Innovation Hub, Akure and supported by Google. It is scheduled to hold between 8th and 10th of August 2013.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested participants can sign-up for the event at &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly.akuremapup&quot;&gt;https://bit.ly.akuremapup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; more information about map ups can be found here. &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/site/mapyourworldcommunity/&quot;&gt;https://sites.google.com/site/mapyourworldcommunity/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.google.com/images/icons/feature/globe_bubbles-256.png&quot; /&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://akure.gdg.ng/blog/map-up-akure</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://akure.gdg.ng/blog/map-up-akure</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
